They're doing human trafficking in the
place, they're doing prostitution,
they're doing drugs, you know. And they
deal with 30 cops.
Right? So, think about it. We're in the
confines of the precinct. If they wanted
to, they could just take me to the back,
shoot me,
leave,
erase the footage, say the camera's not
working. The detective, which is one of
the dirty cops that we're investigating,
will catch the case. He'll come and
investigate, and he'll be like, "Oh,
yeah.
Steven Lee was dirty, and he got shot by
gangsters while getting paid off by
dirty gangsters and stuff."
Easy.
Hi everybody. I'm John Kiriakou, and
welcome back to another episode of Deep
Focus.
First, I want to ask your forgiveness. I
just got off a plane. I'm not shaven. My
hair is all funky and crazy. So, I don't
normally look like a bum. Please accept
my apologies. Second, there are a lot of
things in life that I'm proud of.
We all have things in life that we're
proud of. We're all proud of our
children, for example. But, I'm most
proud, really, of being
a whistleblower.
The life of a whistleblower is hard.
What most Americans don't understand is
that there's actually a legal definition
of whistleblowing. It's bringing to
light any evidence of waste, fraud,
abuse, illegality, or threats to the
public health or public safety. You can
blow the whistle on pretty much anything
at any level of government.
Well, law enforcement is someplace where
we really need whistleblowers. We really
need the honest people to rise up to the
top.
The NYPD, the New York Police
Department, is arguably the largest
police department in the world. It's
actually bigger than most countries'
militaries.
And it has problems, like any big
bureaucracy.
Because it has problems, it needs
whistleblowers.
And today, we have one of the most
important NYPD whistleblowers to come
out of that organization, at least since
Frank Serpico.
Steven Lee blew the whistle and paid for
it not just with his career,
but also with his freedom.
I want him to tell his story, and I want
him to tell us what it was like to be on
the receiving end of the full force of
the New York Police Department. Steven,
welcome to the show. Glad you're with
us.
Hi. How you doing, John? Thank you for
having me. Thanks for doing this. I
think this is important.
You got some uh press,
and actually, it was largely positive
press in the New York City area, but not
a lot of national press. So, for our
viewers who don't know who you are or
what your story is, can you tell us
about your whistleblowing?
Sure. Um
my name is Steven Lee. I'm a former NYPD
sergeant.
Uh
18 years on the force.
Um
So, what happened was
in 2013, when I got promoted to the rank
of sergeant,
I uh got transferred to Flushing,
Queens, which is the 109 Precinct.
And I was there as um conditions
crime sergeant.
Uh
for people that don't know, it's people
that wear the plain clothes.
They go out, they address the precinct
conditions, like, you know, stolen rims
and tires, or stolen GLAs, um
kids hanging out on the corner.
Uh we also do the bar checks. So, that's
the most important part, the bar checks.
Uh liquor licensing and stuff like that.
And when we go into the karaoke, we have
things called we call them KTVs, right?
So, they're like they're karaokes for um
the non-Asians.
KTV means karaoke television. I don't
know why they call it KTV. I guess cuz
they couldn't pronounce karaoke, right?
So, they call it KTV.
Um but in the environment for KTVs, it's
not like Hollywood, like, you know, like
standing on a stage and singing. It's
more of um you get private rooms.
Uh you get bottle service.
You have a mommy son. A mommy son is
like a female pimp, right?
She brings She like It's kind of like uh
that movie Rush Hour, right? With Jackie
Chan and
Chris Rock. Where you get the girls
lined up, they come in,
and then
you know, you pick a girl that you like,
and they sit with you, they drink with
you, they show karaoke, and if you, you
know, if they like you, you get to take
them home and do extra stuff with them,
and you pay them, of course, for it,
right?
Um
We do these bar checks there and stuff
like that. And
when we do the bar checks,
at first, when I'm doing the inspections
and stuff,
they're saying, "Oh, you know, they
don't pay us, so it's kind of like not
illegal, like we cuz I'm thinking
straight off the head, prostitution,
right?"
>> Sure.
But,
the way they they find a way around it
is like, "Oh, it's a tip that they give
us, right? It's like we don't ask them
for the money, quote unquote." But, they
do, right? We don't ask them for the
money, quote unquote, but they give us a
tip if they like our service. And of
course, you know,
they're going to be given a tip, right?
Otherwise, the girl's not going to give
any service. Whatever the case is, um
the bar checks were important because
that's
that was the bread and butter, right? Um
the cops were getting paid off by the
karaokes. So, how my undercover work
started was
we had a new commanding officer come in.
And new commanding officer was brought
in by the police union, the police PBA.
And the reason why the PBA brought in
this particular boss was because the
morale of the precinct was very low.
Um it happens a lot where the white
shirts, we call them,
uh which is lieutenants and above,
they wear white shirts. That's why we
call them white shirts.
Um they're also considered executives in
the NYPD.
And they were the ones that were running
the precinct.
So, usually, um
it's the cops that run the precinct,
right? Because
if the cops shut down,
then you get no more activity,
right? You get no more arrests, you get
no more enforcement.
Um we call it a slow down.
I don't know if they still do those
things, but we call it slow down. So,
it's like whenever a boss um
you know, retaliates against a cop or or
does something bad to a cop,
the union will call for a slow down. So,
the cops will stop doing activity,
they'll respond to 911 calls slower, and
stuff like that. But,
yeah. And that puts that puts lives at
risk.
Yes, it put lives at risk, but it's
mostly because of the quota system,
right? So, the bosses want their quotas.
Um they want their numbers.
But, back on track. So,
the reason why my my work started was um
we had this new commanding officer. He
was cleaning house,
and a lot of lieutenants left,
transferred out. And then, my direct
supervisor,
he refused to transfer out. And at that
time, I didn't know why. I was like,
"Why don't you just leave, you know, go
someplace else?"
Um but, we were going to the pizza shop.
We're driving I'm driving him to the
pizza shop, and we're just having
conversation. He's venting. He's like,
"Oh, this guy, we got to get rid of him,
blah blah blah." And I'm like, "Okay,
why don't you just make a phone call,
right?" Cuz there's a lot of nepotism in
NYPD, right? It basically runs the
department. It's all about who you know,
it's not about what skills you have or
whatever, right? So, I'm like, "Why
don't you call your you know,
call your hook, right?"
And he's like,
"Oh, no, I can't that don't work. This
guy's well-liked up top, too. So, we're
going to have to try something else."
And I'm like, "Try something else? Like,
what do you mean?"
He's like, "Steve, you do these uh
checks in these karaokes and stuff,
right? Like,
you know the girls that work there,
right?" And I'm like, "Yeah, I mean,
I don't know them, but
you know, I'm familiar with them,
right?" And they're like,
he's like, "Yeah, so can maybe you get
one of the girls to say that, you know,
he raped her,
right?"
And I'm like, "Wait, you want to put
fake rape charges on this guy?"
And he's like, "Yeah." So, I'm like,
"All right, sure, sure." So, I brush it
off. So, you know, I'm not going to tell
him no, because
you know, that's my direct supervisor.
So, I I told him, "Yeah, yeah, sure,
sure, whatever." And I just avoided him
for like a week straight.
But, that whole week, he just kept on
bringing it up. "Hey, Steve, you found a
girl yet? Hey, Steve, you found a girl
yet?" And I'm like, "No, no, no, no. Uh
I got to go.
I got a 911 call. I got to go to react
to a call. I got this thing I got to do,
right?" And now, I avoid him.
So, after a week, I decided to knock on
my commanding officer's door.
Um
I walk in, I go, "Sir, you know, I need
to talk to you.
Uh can we have a man-to-man
conversation,
you know, off the books?"
And
there's no such thing as off-the-record
conversations when you're talking to a
supervisor in any department, right? So,
I don't
I don't want anybody to think that
you could have an off-the-record
conversation. There's just there's no
off-the-record conversations. But, I
tried to speak to him man-to-man, like a
locker room kind of talk.
And
>> [clears throat]
>> he's like, "Yeah, sure. Sit down. What's
up?"
I go, "Listen, somebody's trying to jam
you up,
right?" I didn't want to give him
details at the time, you know, I didn't
want to get involved, cuz this was my
dream precinct. I went from a 2-hour
commute to a 5-minute commute, right?
And from a neighborhood
that was high crime to my ethnicity
neighborhood, where, you know, I grew up
in and, you know, like I I in and stuff
like that, where
it was it was it felt good to get back
to my own community,
right? To help my own community.
And that was kind of like my dream,
right? To uh becoming a police officer,
helping my own people out, right?
Um
but
he's like, "Sure, you know, what is it
so I can protect myself?" I go, "Look,
somebody's trying to put fake rape
charges on you."
He goes, "Oh, okay, I think I have an
idea who it is. If I say his name, you
know, just give me a nod or something."
And he says, "Bobby." And I go, "Yes."
Cuz his name is Robert Song, right?
Lieutenant Robert Song, and um they call
him Bobby.
So, I'm like, "Yeah."
He's like, "All right, thanks."
Week later,
he calls me back into his office, and he
goes, "Listen, I I had to drop a log to
Internal Affairs."
And I'm like, "Oh, shit." I thought it
was a off-comers, you know,
off-the-record conversation. He's like,
"No, I had to drop a log to protect
myself. I know you didn't want to get
involved, but they're asking if you
could go on the cover and get it on
recording."
>> [snorts]
>> And I go, "Well, do I have a choice?"
He goes, "Well, you don't really tell
Internal Affairs no,
right? Because then you become the
target."
All right. So, I go, "All right, I'm
being volun-told." So, there's a thing
that we say in the NYPD where it's like,
you know, you're technically
volunteering, but you're actually being
told to do it, right? So,
I'm like, "Listen, what do I do?"
All right, on your day off, on your
audio, regular day off, on your audio,
they'll come to your house, and, you
know, they'll interview you, and they'll
get the get the story, and you just tell
them what what happened. Sure.
Day off, they interview me.
Two people, one a sergeant, one a
lieutenant.
Um they come and interview me.
They leave.
Next day, they come interview me again.
This time they brought their their
commanding officer
talking to them.
They set me up.
Fine, we'll give you devices, and, you
know, you go and get this
on recording.
So,
I get the devices, I'm going on
recording. Uh I bump This we call a
bump.
All right, when you when you try to
engage with a target, we call it a bump.
So, We do it the CIA as well.
Oh, yeah, it's called bump also?
>> a bump. You bump somebody.
Yeah, so, the bump is is not you
physically actually bumping a person,
but it's like you you engage with the
person, you try to start a conversation,
or you try to, you know, get what you're
looking for.
So, I would walk into his office, and
I'm like, "Hey, you know, you on blue.
Let me talk to you about that thing that
we were talking about." He was like,
"What are you talking about?" And I'm
like, "You know, the thing with um the
CO." And he's like, "Okay."
So, usually it's him engaging me and me
avoiding him, so
I guess it felt kind of weird for me to
um
engage him on it.
And I'm like, "Yeah, I found a girl, you
know, she said, you know, she's willing
to do it, whatever, blah blah." And he's
like, "Oh."
Sits back,
smiles,
and then he just becomes silent.
So, I already I already knew this guy
his, you know, spidey senses are up,
right? That's right.
So, I'm like, "Let me not push you too
hard, you know, cuz then I look stupid
and look suspicious, right? So, I'm just
like, all right, well, let me know if
you want What do you want to do?"
And he's like,
"Okay."
All right. So, I leave. I go back,
and I tell my handlers, "Look,
Something's up. Somebody Somebody tipped
him off, or he suspects you."
I look stupid, you know, he he's look
he's thinking I'm looking at me
suspicious and everything.
So, what ended up happening was they're
like, you know, all right, go hang out
with him off duty, and maybe when you
guys are drunk or whatever, he'll, you
know, mention more at the dinner or
something like that, you know.
So,
you know, Lieutenant Song liked to hang
out at karaokes,
right? In the precinct, in the confines
of the precinct. So, off duty, you know,
I'm like, "Hey, where you going, Lou?
You know, you're going to go out and
drink? Oh, let's go and hang out, you
know, I heard that this place has new
girls. Let's go check them out, you
know, maybe, you know, do some
undercover work or something, blah blah,
you know."
And he liked going to specific places,
so he was like, "Yeah, all right, fine,
you know, we'll go to a spot." We went
to a spot.
Um it's called CEO.
Uh it's one of the places on College
Point
in Flushing, and uh this guy named Jimmy
owned it. All right.
And
Jimmy um Jimmy set us up outside, and
when I went there, though, it was it
wasn't just the lieutenant, it was
detectives that were there, people from
different units, vice, narcotics,
um you know, people in the Detective
Bureau,
uh people in from the shooting range,
like, different precincts.
It was a bunch of cops.
So,
the cops are all drinking, you know,
then Jimmy gets us a room, and, you
know, we're drinking, we're hanging out,
whatever.
And the rape thing doesn't come on. It
doesn't come up. The topic doesn't come
up, all right? Cuz I'm I'm I'm like,
"I'm look, why don't we get one of these
girls?" And he's just like ignores me
and starts drinking and talking about
other stuff.
He's trying to have fun, he's not trying
to talk. So, I'm like, all right, I tell
my handlers, "This is what happened."
They're like, "Okay, you know, just keep
going out with him, maybe he'll get used
to you, you know, you get closer to
him."
Fine.
As I'm going out and getting closer to
him, though,
the the setting changes. It goes from
like,
instead of being by the bar, we're like
in a private room now.
Um there's girls, you know, they're
they're
it's it's it's a bad scene, right? It's
like um
it's like if you've seen like really
male chauvinistic
uh bad gangsters, just the way they
treat women, like, it's just
"Come over here." Just grabs them, and
then just starts groping them and stuff
like that, and dry humping them on the
speaker, take them to the bathroom and
and raping them and and
there's there's, you know,
familiar faces in community where I knew
I know like, I arrested this person
before, or this person wanted for
something, you know, like, he's a known
criminal, whatever. And they're in there
sniffing ketamine and cocaine and stuff,
you know, smoking weed and everything,
and I'm like,
"The [__] did I walk into?"
Right?
So, I go back and I tell my handlers,
"Listen, you still You sure you want to
go do this? Cuz you're opening up a
whole can of worms here, you know, it's
not just this rape charge we're talking
about. There's a lot of criminality
going on, all right? So, if we're going
to do this, I want to know that you guys
have my back, that we're going to fully
do this, right? Cuz it's not just this
lieutenant that's involved. You have
other people from different units, and
multiple cops, right? It was at least
maybe like 20 cops that I seen within
the first couple months, right? And I
told them, "Look, it's not just these
cops, because
you have, yeah, detectives and and
police officers, but you have mostly
lieutenants, captains, and chiefs,
right?"
And they're like, "Yeah, yeah, yeah,
yes, don't worry about it. Let's go
straight to the police commissioner.
You're You're the most protected cop in
the NYPD right now, you know, um just go
out and do it." And I was like, "Yeah,
but
nobody can know, right?"
Cuz I'm technically undercover. I'm a
uniform police officer, uniform
sergeant, supervisor, playing
a dirty cop to get into the inner
circle, right? So, the way the NYPD's
broken down is I I like to put them in
different circles, right? Um you have
the outer circle, which is regular cops
that, you know, just doing their day job
and going home at the day, you know,
they just want to be police officers,
want to do their job, want to go home.
Then you have cops that have um hooks,
we call them, right? Or cranes, right?
Like, depending how big their the the
person they know.
And that person that they know will help
them get them transferred to units that
they want to go to, or help them get out
of trouble when they do get into, you
know, trouble and stuff like that. And
those are called, you know, hooks,
right? The people that hooked up.
Then you have the inner circle,
the core people.
These are
chess movers,
right? Cuz everybody on
Sad to say this, but everybody's kind of
like on a chessboard, and everybody is
is chess pieces,
right? All the cops are like chess
pieces.
But you have certain people that can can
move chess pieces, right? We call them
chess movers.
Meaning they have enough juice to
control what happens,
right? And these are the inner core
people.
And the inner core people,
it could it's not just one precinct,
it's it's happening everywhere in every
precinct.
Inner core people, they're hooked up
with chiefs, or they're hooked up with,
you know, deputy commissioners or mayors
and stuff like that, right? Because it's
politics that corrupt
um the department, right? Which I think
should be totally separate. Policing and
politics should be totally separated.
Also, I also believe that the NYPD
should not be monitoring itself.
Internal Affairs is is is all smoke and
mirrors. It's not there for, you know,
um fighting corruption. It's actually
there for damage control and saving face
for the NYPD, right?
Like uh like
uh public relations. Right.
>> Right.
So, they know where all the corruption
is. It's just they don't want to do
anything about it, because it's kind of
like if you clean up all the corruption,
you shock the system to the point where
it can't operate anymore. So, they As we
saw in the '70s.
We That's exactly what happened in New
York in the '70s. The the whole the
whole police department was paralyzed
because of the corruption
investigations.
>> Right. Like like Frank Serpico, right? I
speak to Frank Serpico all the time and
we compare stories back and forth and he
said this is exactly the same thing that
was going on. Nothing changed. Yeah, 50
years ago. It changes only the players,
right? So,
I don't know what it is. I think it's
just the way the system is set up or
whatever to operate, but it just
self-preserves, right? So, whatever the
case is, um
uh the inner circle or core people that
are actually
it is driven by greed, power,
um
and it is just totally it's disgusting
what what it what they're able to do
and what they get away with.
Okay?
So, like I don't know if you follow the
news lately what happened with the past
administration with the mayor with Mayor
Adams
>> and his administration. Yeah.
>> Oh, sure.
>> where all the corruption come
>> corrupt. Yeah, he was corrupt.
And the people around him were
>> that came out Yep. it was kind of the
kind of like a glimmer of the surface,
right?
And you could see like the police
commissioner and his brother was is
under investigation by the feds now for
extortion of the nightclubs and stuff
like that. And that was the same setup
that this lieutenant used,
right? Whereas you have retired cops set
up a security company and he would do
security for the the nightclubs and
stuff and if you don't use the security
company, then you would get checked
regularly and you know, they would
summons you and harass you basically,
right? And so,
this is the the setup they went through.
All right, so whatever the case is,
that's how they filter the money, right?
To legally say, "Oh, no, we're just
doing security." But whatever the case
is, um
those are the three circles and for me
to get into the inner circle, I had to
pretend to be like them,
right? They're not going to let somebody
who's a true believer or like, you know,
um
somebody who's
not as dirty as them
to get into that inner circle. And they
were like, "Okay, figure out which which
which karaoke owner would be the best
one to flip. Which which one more likely
to flip?" I go, "Jimmy."
Jimmy's a snake.
You know, Jimmy's a snake and he'll do
anything to survive, you know, um
he's here legally
and you know, he has the most to lose,
right?
And they're like, "All right, start
approaching Jimmy."
So, I started approaching Jimmy and I
start telling him, "Oh, yeah, you know,
short on cash, yeah, I got a lot of
pressure, need to find some way to make
some, you know, extra money, you know,
whatever."
And he's like, right away, felt so
comfortable,
"Oh,
I'll make you a partner in in the
business and, you know,
you I'll pay you like $2,000 a month
and, you know,
all you have to do is like, you know,
just keep these riffraffs out and, you
know, just you know, make sure I don't
get any tickets or just let me know when
you guys can do a check or whatever and
stuff like that." And I was like,
"All right, you know, sounds good." I go
back to my handlers, I tell them,
they're like, "Great, do it."
They felt so comfortable
paying off cops and it happened, I
guess, so regularly
that they would pay me off in public.
We would be we would be sitting at a tea
house, right? And we're sitting there
and in the Chinese tea house you had a
and it was like one of those high-end
tea houses. So, you have a a server just
standing there,
right? Waiting to pour tea for you and
stuff like that. A server standing
there. I'm sitting there in uniform,
full uniform,
on my lunch break, right? With, of
course, internal affairs, you know,
waiting.
It's operation, right? So, I'm sitting
in full uniform.
Jimmy's partner's on my left side,
Jimmy's on my right side.
His partner's sitting right next to me
here on a it's like a I guess it's a
two-seater couch, right? And Jimmy's
sitting on a like a single sitting couch
and he's on my right side.
And then the plan was, "Oh, I need to
shut down my competition because,
you know, business is not good and, you
know, they're they're selling things
that are lower price because they're
laundering money and, you know, they're
doing online gambling and drugs and
prostitution. That's how they launder
the money. They sell the bottles
cheaper, but on paper they're putting it
for more or whatever and stuff like
that."
Like, "All right, whatever. I don't
care. What do you want me to do?" He's
like, "Oh, I need you to shut them down,
you know, get their liquor license taken
away, revoked and stuff like that."
And I would tell my handlers and then
they would do operations, whatever, and
it wouldn't go well, right? So, the
point the it came down to the point
where
Jimmy would give me drugs
and I would plant them there
and then say, "Hey, we found drugs."
Then we could shut them down.
So,
Jimmy's partner
hand me some
ketamine,
right? It was
clearly. It was like in a red bag.
Opens up the red bag
and he just pours it I'm like, "What is
that?" And I'm like, you know, reaching
for the red bag and he just pours it
into my hand.
It was like jars of ketamine.
And I'm like, "What the [__] are you
doing? Like, we're in public."
And the the the the girl is just looking
at me, like the server. She's just
looking at me. She's just like,
"Whatever. I don't see anything."
Right?
So, I'm like, "Oh, come on. You can't do
this in public." He's like, "Oh, no, no,
don't worry. It's all right. It's all
right."
And I'm like, "You guys feel so
comfortable
to just pay me off in public and give me
drugs in public,
right?" Then Jimmy just shoves a
envelope into my my pants pocket, right?
While he's giving me the drugs.
So, I'm like, "What the [__] is going
on? Like, these guys are just way too
comfortable." So, I I go back to
internal affairs, I give them
everything. I tell them this is what
happened.
They're like, "Oh, this is great. Okay,
great."
So, I'm like, "All right, so you're
going to plant the drugs here?" "No, no,
no, we're going to voucher it and we're
going to safeguard it and then, you
know, we're going to add it to the
charges and stuff like that."
I'm like, "All right, cool."
A week later the place gets shut down.
I get excluded from operation,
right?
Um what happened end up happening was
they
internal affairs sent an undercover up
there
and they had the drugs on them and all
of a sudden they find five jars of
ketamine, which is the same five jars
that I got. But they they claim that it
wasn't the same. They claimed, "Oh, no,
they actually found it at the place."
And I'm like, "Come on, I'm not [__]
5 years old. You know what I mean? I can
put two and two together."
So, they shut down the place. I go back
to Jimmy. Jimmy ends up giving me
$10,000 in cash. So,
the regular payment was around $2,000 in
cash every month for every spot that
they own, every karaoke that they have
that we're protecting.
And then $10,000 in cash whenever you
did a special favor like, um
get somebody off an arrest,
um
you um help cover up like a overdose or
something like that or a bar fight or
whatever it is.
Uh you take down the competition,
apparently,
and they give you $10,000 in cash, all
right? I I end up
doing that for like
almost a year until they arrested Jimmy,
right?
It was hard. It was it was it was tiring
because Risky?
>> basically working two jobs, right? I was
going in I had to still do my regular
appearances and, you know, work my
regular job to, you know, like I'm
sergeant in the NYPD. I had to do my
job, obviously, right?
And then after hours I would have to go
and hang out and, you know, do my
undercover work.
And there was a couple of times
where I knew I couldn't um trust
internal affairs
was
2 months into the operation,
the chief's driver,
all right?
Bosses have drivers.
Drive them around and stuff.
Um
the chief's driver.
I saw him at one one of the karaokes.
Asian guy also, all right? Um
I see him there. I'm not too familiar
with him at the time. I wasn't that
close to him and he's like, "Hey, Steve,
you know, come on in, have a shot."
I'm like, "How do you know my name?
Like, I know your name, but I don't know
you like that, right? So, why are you
inviting me to come in? Two, I'm in
uniform
and I'm talking to the security guard
cuz the security guard was my my CI, my
confidential informant. He would tell me
like, "Oh, this person's in here or this
this one of the persons here or that
person has a gun or that person has
drugs, whatever." He would give me the
heads up.
And I'm talking to him and then,
you know, the guy is going inside. He's
like, "Oh, come in." He went inside,
came back out. "Hey, Steve, come on,
come on in." I'm like, "No, I'm good.
I'm working. I can't." He's like, "Okay,
okay, don't worry about it." He's like,
"Look,
you know, it's actually probably good
that you don't come in cuz, you know,
your boss came to meet with my my boss
and they had a conversation. So, my
commanding officer, who's ranked as a
captain, had a conversation with the
chief, right? And he said my name came
up and that internal affairs is doing
the operation and he and then my chief
asks, you know, the driver, he said, "My
chief asked me my boss asked me if you
were okay guy." And I told him yeah, you
were good, right?
Cuz we were in the Asian Jade Society,
which is like a fraternal society in in
NYPD. That's how I knew him.
So, I'm like, "All right, thanks.
Whatever."
He's like, "No, no, but seriously,
internal affairs is watching you, so be
careful."
I'm like, "What the [__] internal
affairs watching me for? Internal
affairs watching you. Get the [__] out
of my face. You're the one that's
corrupt, right?"
I try to play it off.
I immediately turned back to my I I got
scared cuz I'm like, "Why is the
operation leaking out? You assured me
that only my handlers would know, only
my commanding officer knew and your
commanding officer and went straight up
to the chief after that. Like, only
certain people were supposed to know.
Why people know about the operation,
right?" Yeah. I immediately called my
handlers. My handlers don't pick up. I
call my commanding officer. My
commanding officer is like, "Oh, so what
did he say?" I told him what he said.
He's like, "Okay, cuz I had a meeting
with the chief cuz she's my direct
um
supervisor. So, I have to, you know,
report to her if there's a operation or
whatever in precinct.
But let me talk to internal affairs and
the commissioner and see what what we
could do get around that."
>> Oh my god. So, after that, he stopped
reporting to the chief.
All right? The commissioner was like,
"Don't don't report to her no more,
right?" So, fine.
And by commissioner, I don't mean
Bratton at the time. I meant
um the the commissioner of internal
affairs.
All right?
So, whatever the case, that was the
one-time leak. Second time a leak was
um
I was in the precinct. Internal affairs
was doing overtime. And this is a unit
from Brooklyn. I was in Queens. And they
usually do out-of-borough overtime where
they go and get these unlicensed massage
places and then they claim that they
were doing prostitution and stuff
because of language barrier and all
those other stuff. They're easy to
catch. So, it's like they go in and they
go, "Okay." They They speak in English,
"Hey, you know, how much is it for sex?"
or whatever. And a lot of the workers
don't speak Chinese uh don't speak
English. So, they're like, "Yes, yes,
yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, sit down, sit
down, yes, yes, yes, yes, right?"
And
they take it as, "Okay, they said yes,
right? We can arrest them.
Prostitution."
Which is [__] right? A lot of times
it's [__] But they do it for
overtime.
And each body they they arrest, they get
like 3 hours overtime, right? So,
um
I knew this guy that when I used to work
in Brooklyn, I knew him and he's a
sergeant now and he's a sergeant in
internal affairs for Brooklyn.
And he We had a conversation on the
side. I'm like, "Hey, how you doing? How
you been?" You know, he's like, "Oh, I'm
great, you know, I'm just doing some
overtime, whatever."
For some reason, he goes, "Hey Steve,
you know,
stop Don't hang out in these uh
karaokes, you know, cuz I guess he heard
that I was hanging out in the karaokes.
He's like, "Don't hang out in these
karaokes, you know." And he named
certain ones that we were doing
operations in.
And he goes, "Stop hanging out in these
karaokes cuz internal affairs got
operations going on in them."
And I go,
"How do you know?"
All right? He's like, I was like, "How
do you know? Aren't you in Brooklyn?"
And he's like,
"Yeah, but I have a friend in the Queens
group and he told me."
All right?
After maybe 6 months into the operation
or something like that, right? I The
timeline gets fuzzy cuz it's it's 2
years I was undercover, right? So, it's
somewhere midway through the the the
undercover work where I meet up with my
lieutenant.
I go in. My lieutenant when as soon as
they walk into the karaoke room, he
goes, "Let me see your phone."
And I'm like, "What?"
He's like, "Let me see your phone." I'm
like, "Okay, cool." I give him my phone.
You know, I had a new phone at the time.
I didn't Maybe he wanted to check it
out. He's like, "Unlock it."
I'm like, "What do you want, my girl?
Like, what the [__] you going through my
phone for?" And he's like, "Just unlock
it." Fine. I unlock it.
Luckily,
at that time, I was so paranoid already,
right? That I would delete my phone
calls from internal affairs. I would
delete my text messages from internal
affairs. They also had put an app on my
phone where they could send a text
message and turn on my camera and my mic
at any time, right? Because me picking
up the devices from them
was just getting stupid. It was We kept
on meeting at same same place, 7-Eleven.
Kept on being the same My handler kept
on dropping it off. And we kept on doing
the same thing where it was stand by the
the Slurpee machine and he'll put in the
empty cup and I'll take the cup and I'll
take it out of the cup and I'll get a
Slurpee and then I'll go to the cash
register.
It It kept on being so routine where
the cash register person even knew that
he was a cop.
Oh my god.
>> the cash register guy was like, "Yo,
that's a cop."
And I go,
"What do you mean?" Cuz he knows who's
the regulars are cuz 7-Eleven is our
spot, right? Where they do the right
thing. They give you discounts or they
give you free Slurpees or coffee and
stuff like that. So, we would go there
all the time, right? So, he knew who the
people work in in the 109 were. So, when
a new person comes in,
he would be like, "That guy kind of
suspicious. Like, is he really a cop?
Does he really work with you guys?" cuz
we don't see this guy often, right?
So, he goes that he's a cop. I go, "How
do you know?" He goes, "I saw his gun
and his shield when he was
gassing up."
All right? And I go, "Great."
So, I told them that. And I'm like,
"Look, we can't do this no more cuz if
one,
my driver
is getting suspicious why the [__] I'm
keep going to 7-Eleven getting Slurpees
in the [__] winter, right?
Yeah.
>> Two,
every time we go there, he's starting to
notice you and he's like, "Why is this
guy always here when we come here?"
Three, the cash register even [__]
identified you, right? So, we got to try
something else. So, they Their tech team
had this new technology. It was new at
the time, right? Cuz this is 2013, 2014,
right?
Where they had an app where they put on
the phone and they could just send text
message and automatically turns on your
camera and your and your um
your your microphone. I was paranoid
whenever they sent me a text turn on the
camera and stuff and I would delete the
text messages and I saved the
my handlers' names under different
names, right? So, it didn't Just in case
he recognized the name and knew, "Wait,
I know this person. He's in internal
affairs, right?" I would change the
names.
So, he went through my phone. He went
through my text messages.
Went through my phone calls. Went
through my pictures. Went through my
email.
And I'm like, "What the [__] you doing?"
All right? Give me my phone. Give What
the [__] you doing? He gives back my
phone. He goes, "No, you're good."
I'm like, "What the [__] was that
about?"
He goes, "I think we got a rat." And I
go, "Why the [__] you going through my
phone?"
All right? I tried to play it off. I'm
like, "So, what the [__] you going
through my phone?"
He's like, "No, I had to check
everybody. I checked everybody."
And I go, "All right, so who the [__]
you think the rat is? Like, what
Who you think it is?" He's like, "I
think it's Jimmy."
I'm like, "Oh.
So, why the [__] are we here?"
All right? Why we at Jimmy's spot?
That's why we're here to find out.
So, I go walk out. I look around. I go
outside.
Have a cigarette.
Looking around. I'm like, "All right."
Make a phone call.
Call my handlers. Call my handlers.
No answer.
I call my commanding officer.
Finally picks up. I go, "Where is
everybody? I need help.
This guy just went through my [__]
phone. I think I'm burned. I think he
knows. He thinks Jimmy's a you know,
a rat whatever and stuff like that. So,
he might know that Jimmy's working with
us and everything and then he gives me
up, I'm [__] right? So, get me out."
He's like, "All right, let me call you
Let me call the group and see what's
going on."
Calls the group. They don't answer.
This is like around maybe midnight-ish.
Um so, I had to hang out with with the
lieutenant. I'm stuck there hanging out
with him drinking. And I'm like, "All
right, I'm going to go." It's like 3:00
in the morning. I'm like, "I got to go.
I got next I got a shift tomorrow, you
know, I got a day tour tomorrow. I got
to go."
Fine. I go I go home. Get home like
around 3:00 in the morning.
Then I get a phone call.
All right? It's from my my handler, the
sergeant. He goes, "Hey big guy, you
called?"
I go, "Yeah, where were you guys?" He
goes, "What do you mean? I just got into
work. You know, I have a family, too,
whatever." And I go,
"Yeah, but the operation started at, you
know, 2200 hours. Like,
it's 0300. Like, you know, it's started
at 10:00 p.m. It's 3:00 in the morning
now. Like, where were you guys? Who was
out there watching me then?"
And he's like, "Oh, nobody's out there
watching you, big guy. You're a big guy.
Don't worry. You can handle yourself."
I go, "Are you [__] kidding me?
You send me in
to a, you know, a dirty karaoke place,
right? Where all this
illegal activity is happening. Run by
gangsters, like Chinese triad gangsters.
These are the same people that, you
know, during the bus wars in Chinatown
shot up, you know, people and shot them
up, put them in suitcases
and left them at the bus depot. You All
right?
They're doing human trafficking in the
place. They're doing prostitution.
They're doing drugs, you know, and
they're there with 30 cops, right? So,
think about it. We're in the confines of
the precinct. If they wanted to, they
could just take me to the back, shoot
me,
leave,
erase the footage, say the camera's not
working. The detective, which is one of
the 30 cops that we were investigating,
will catch the case. He'll come and
investigate and he'll be like, "Oh yeah,
Steven Lee was dirty and he got shot by
gangsters while getting paid off by
dirty gangsters and stuff." Mhm. Easy.
Right?
Right.
And you guys aren't there
to to to protect me or or or clear my
name on it, right?
So, I'm like, "So, what happened with
the phone? Who sent the text message to
my phone to turn my phone on?"
Right?
I was like, "Did you get any recordings
and stuff?"
Then all of a sudden, it's like, "Oh uh
yeah, we we got some recordings, but it
was unclear cuz the music in the in the
room was too loud and some of the stuff
we couldn't hear." I'm like, "You're
just [__] [__] You didn't get
[__] You guys were [__] home
sleeping, getting overtime for this
[__] and you weren't watching me,
right?" So, from that point on, I knew I
couldn't trust internal affairs. That
I'm on my own out there, right? Where
it's like I'm deep cover. I'm out there
on my own and my life is in danger and I
have to protect myself. So, I end up
going to the street,
right? So, I knew some people that I
that in the neighborhood that I knew
that used to be gangsters and stuff like
that or that, you know, had some kind of
dark past, but they reformed and they're
like, you know, legit now and they're
trying to do good for the community,
give back and stuff like that. So, I
knew some of these people, and I'm
talking to them like, "Look, this is
what's going on.
I might need your protection if things
go south."
All right? And they're like, "Steve,
Chinese Chinese gangs, they work
differently, right?"
They go, "Steve,
>> [clears throat]
>> we don't like dirty cops.
All right?
We understand you're a cop, and you do
your thing, all right? But, you know, we
don't like dirty cops. So,
it's either you're white or you're
black. You can't be gray.
All right? And don't worry, we got your
back."
And from that point, you know, at least
I knew I had somebody watch my back in
case the gangsters want to retaliate
against me cuz if, you know, the cops
retaliate against me, I realized I At
that time, it didn't hit me that they
could go that far where they could send
me to prison and stuff like that, right?
I I didn't think it would go that far.
So, in the case is under the after the
operations, uh you know, after 2 years,
we end up arresting the lieutenant and
the detective. Um internal affairs
[__] up the case so bad
where the DA had to give them deals on
misdemeanor charges instead of felony
charges. They're supposed to get felony
charges and 1 year jail time, and
instead, the DA had to give misdemeanor
charges and 1 year probation. Oh my god.
And then they went after you is the
issue. Before we go on to our next
question, uh a word from our sponsors. A
digital dollar has the potential to let
the government track every transaction
you make, freeze your account without a
court order, restrict what you can
purchase, automatically deduct fines or
taxes, even put an expiration date on
your own savings.
I'm not saying that that's the plan, but
I'm saying that's the capability.
And once that infrastructure exists,
history shows that it gets used. That's
why I've partnered with American
Alternative Assets to bring you a free
report called the digital dollar trap.
It breaks down what's being built, who's
behind it, and how physical gold could
help protect your savings from a system
designed for control.
Go to johnlovesgold.com
to download your free copy or call
1-888-GOLD-053
to request one by mail. That's
johnlovesgold.com
or 888-GOLD-053.
Steven,
at this point in your life, things are
starting to get a little hairy, and I
got to tell you,
I've I've been there. I remember like
the instant
that I realized, "Wait a minute, they're
investigating me."
And things were never the same after
that. So, start there. Tell us about
your your into this now for 2 years.
You're trying to do the right thing.
You're working with internal affairs to
bring essentially crooked cops to
justice.
And then you realize, "This isn't
working out the way it's supposed to."
Take it from there.
Yes, sir. So,
after we arrested the lieutenant and the
detective, um
I was actually upset that they decided
to cut the undercover work early, right?
Cuz to me, I was just getting into that
inner circle, that core that I was
telling you about. And I told them,
"Look, man, I'm I'm just getting in
there, and I just started, you know,
investigating
um the chief's driver and and other
lieutenants from different precincts and
different units, like vice units and
stuff like that, and um
you know, those higher-ups I was getting
introduced to who was actually
protecting them and stuff like that.
And they were like, "No, the chiefs want
to shut it down." Um
you know, at first, they didn't even
want to go after the criminality, right?
They were just going after
administrative charges. They just want
to slap a hand on the wrist and then,
you know, transfer them out and call it,
you know, call it a day, but
I was like, you know, this is this is
not right. You know, tell them that
we're about to get to the root of the,
you know, of the core of this.
And
one thing that hit me, um
when what they told me was, "Steve,
fighting corruption is like fighting the
war on drugs. You take one drug dealer
off the corner, another one's going to
pop up."
And I was at that time,
uh I was
I was a true true believer, right? Where
internal affairs are the good guys and
all that stuff.
And I realized after all this like how
naive I was, right? It's all an
illusion.
And I told them, my exact words were,
"What are you [__] crazy? Like,
that's why you got to chop off the head,
right? It's like going after, you know,
instead of going after the drug dealer
on the corner, you go after the cartel,
or, you know, you you cut off the
supply,
right? Or, you know,
and they just they just shook their
head. They're like, "No, it doesn't work
like that." All right?
Um
I understand it more now, of course,
because now I understand like, you know,
there's politics involved, and if you
keep going up, it's just going to keep
going up and up and up and up, and it's
not going to stop anywhere, right?
Um
what end up happening was after I said
that,
being the true believer, I kept on
pushing the issue.
All right? One, it was it was my
community that they were
destroying and poisoning.
Um two, during the investigation, I seen
different incidents where the system
failed to protect its people and failed
to actually do its job, right?
And
I want to fix it.
But,
you know,
now I realize it's it's
not fixable, right? It's just the wheel
keeps turning, and we just have to
get what we get, right?
And um
I'm sorry. It's just thinking about it
is just, you know, it's just PTSD is
bringing up a lot.
>> absolutely, and I I understand that. I
And that actually leads me to ask you
this question. I Like you, I'm friendly
with Frank Serpico. Frank Serpico is one
of the giants of the 20th century. I I
put Frank up there with with, you know,
the greatest whistleblowers of the 20th
century, Daniel Ellsberg, for example.
Frank was actually shot in the face,
Yes.
>> and his and his
police colleagues
didn't even call an ambulance. They
wanted him to die in this drug
operation. Did you fear for your safety
when you realized that this deck was
secretly stacked against you?
Did you fear for your safety out there
on the street?
Yes, absolutely.
So, during my my investigation, when I
told you that I realized there was
nobody out there backing me up.
In hindsight,
I could see all the situations they put
me in and why they put me in those
situations where they wanted me to
They wanted my undercover work to fail,
one. And they wanted me to put me in
danger,
right? Um
so,
you see later on
like
after after all this, I went to internal
affairs   for my safety.
I was wiped from the system. I was I was
like a true ghost where if you punch in
my name to the system, like it's like I
I stopped existing.
And that right away blew my cover. I was
burned straight straight out of the bat.
Everybody knew it was me. They're like,
"What happened to Sergeant Lee? How come
he's not here? How come he show up for
work next day?
You know, where is he? We can't find him
in the computer and stuff like that."
And all this other stuff, right? So,
right off the bat, it they knew it was
me. They assured me when my undercover
work began that that wasn't going to
happen, that, you know, Jimmy was going
to be the person that was going to be
the informant, and I would be referred
to as UC-5073,
which is the number they assigned me at
the time, right? And
and so forth.
So, I went to internal affairs. I was
there for like about, uh maybe close to
2 years also.
And
there's where I realized who's the rat
that snitched me out.
The internal affairs is nothing but
smoke and mirrors, right? We have a
saying, even other good even good police
officers
say all the time,
"It's all smoke and mirrors. It's all
[__] It's all show and pony uh
horse and pony show." You know, it's
it's all
it's all there to save face for the
NYPD, right? Where
if they really truly fought corruption,
it would shock the system and
destroy the credibility of NYPD. Also,
you have to remember, the legality of it
is
if all these police officers are
arrested, then people that they
previously convicted can also file for
appeal Absolutely.
>> and say, "Hey, look, this guy is a
corrupt police officer. I was framed."
And so forth or targeted and so forth
and so on, right?
Now,
the scary part is,
keep this in mind, if they could do this
to me,
imagine what they could do to the
average citizen. Mhm.
Yeah, you weren't just some kid off the
street. You were a sergeant.
>> Right, exactly. I I was a police officer
for 8 years before I got promoted. In a
very busy precinct. So, I learned how to
handle, you know, high-stress
situations, um murders,
armed robberies, commercial robberies,
stick-ups, you know, hostage situations.
I learned all that in Brooklyn, and it
was very tough streets, very, you know,
very busy precinct. Great cops I worked
with. For some reason, the busy
precincts, I guess they don't have time
for the [__] and they don't have
time to, you know, scheme all this
corruption and stuff like that. So, the
slower precincts are more prone to
corruption and stuff, right? And it's
not just the precinct I worked in. It's
every precinct has their own
own scam going on,
right? Internal affairs knows about all
of it.
It's just they choose not to go after it
because it's not going to hit them in
the it's not going to hit the press,
right? So, the busier precincts, they're
just busy answering 911 calls one after
the other, one after the other. They
don't have time to socialize with the
businesses, the business owners. They
don't have time to socialize with people
in in the community and stuff like that.
And therefore, they less um they have
less time to be recruited.
Right? So, the recruitment goes like
this, right? It's like
Okay, I'm a business owner. You come
into my business. I give you free
coffee. I give you free food, right? We
engage in conversations.
Then it's like, "Oh, yeah, you know,
how's your family? How's the holidays?
Oh, you know, stuff like that. How's it
going?" Then all of a sudden it becomes,
"Oh, you know, um
I got this ticket. Can you look at it
for me?" And then they'll be like, "All
right, you know what? Since I like this
place, since I come here, you take care
of me, you give me you give the cops
discounts or, you know, you give them
free coffee or whatever. Don't worry
about it. We'll make it go away." Right?
Then it becomes, you know, they try to
target in on whoever helps the most. Cuz
most some cops will be like, "Nah,
sorry, I can't do anything." Right?
Other cops, you know, they'll try to
exculpate to the person.
And those are the people that are
recruitable.
Right? Like you would say. They're
recruitable. So, they spend more time
and effort on that person where it's
like, "Oh, you know, here, take this for
your kid, you know, for Christmas or
here, you know, you you you have a
family a wedding or dinner or whatever.
Don't worry, come here, it's on us. I'll
take care of you, whatever and stuff
like that." And they become closer and
closer, then it becomes, "Oh, you know,
my nephew got arrested. Can you help me
out here or whatever, blah blah." And it
becomes like they try to approach it
where it's like legal and they don't
come out saying, "Hey, look,
he was a major drug dealer and stuff
like that, whatever." You know what I
mean? But
it it they start to see where how far
they could uh
push you.
Right? And then it becomes like, "Okay,
you become so close where it's like,
hey, you know, why don't we go into
business together, you know? And we can
make money together." And then you
become a partner.
Right? Meanwhile, they got you on
payroll. That's what it really is.
Right? So, when you have more time on
your hands, you're able to engage with
people like that more. But in busier
precincts, you're answering call from
call. You're just running from one job
to the other. You don't even have time
to eat. Right? Most of the time. So,
um
when I'm hap- So, that's how it is in
slow precincts and busier precincts. But
after I went to internal affairs, I saw
the people that was there. I saw how
they operated. I saw the secret like
quote-unquote secret programs that they
had to get around warrants and stuff
like that. So,
law enforcement
don't don't be fooled where you think
government agencies need warrants.
All right?
There are several ways to get around
that now, right? Especially with social
media and everything online now. So, you
have social media that gathers your
information, right? And they sell it
to private companies.
Right? Private investigative companies.
And these private investigative
companies, they open up firms and then
what happens is the NYPD or the FBI or
something like that will purchase a
contract with that company, right? Where
the company supplies them the
information.
So, if I if they punch in my phone
number,
all my calls will pop up, all who I
call, who they call,
you know, where I've been, my social
media, all this information will pop up.
And they don't need a warrant for that
because it's not them personally
gathering the information. They're
buying it from a third-party company.
That's their that's their you know,
their loophole. It's the same thing with
license plate readers, right? When
license plate readers first came out, we
were asked like, "Don't we need a
warrant to run somebody's plate for no
reason?" And they go, "No, because this
all this information that's popping up
is coming from a third-party company and
that's that's the loophole." Like they
purchased the information from a
third-party company. All right?
So, I see all this information, all
these violations of rights and stuff.
And
I was kind of like getting turned off
about it. And then I realized internal
affairs is actually more dirtier than
the cops in the street.
Because there's nobody monitoring them.
Right? So, here here's the circle jerk.
You have NYPD that's monitored by
internal affairs.
But who monitors internal affairs?
Internal affairs is broken up into many
groups. Right?
You have group one which monitors
internal affairs members and captains
and above.
That right there should be a red flag.
Right?
But who monitors group one?
You have group 25 that work with the
feds.
Right? So, if FBI has a case on somebody
or CIA or whatever the CIA rarely has
some a case against a cop, but let's say
FBI most of the time or DEA or something
like that has a case against NYPD
officer, right?
Group 25 will work with with the feds.
It's like a joint task force. Right?
But the feds don't trust the NYPD. They
don't trust local police departments.
So, with good reason.
And the only thing that they supply with
is like work schedules and like, you
know, um credentials and stuff like
that. Right? So,
who what who monitors group 25?
Group 25 monitors group one and group
one monitors group 25 because they're
internal affairs members.
So, it's like you watch me, I watch you.
It's basically a circle jerk, right?
Because one day you're working with
group one in group one, and next day
you're group working in group 25, and
next day you're working in the precinct.
So, it's like
you're you're you're not going to rat on
your own friend or your own brother,
right? Or sister in in a department. So,
that's the problem right there. And when
I saw that problem, you know, I was like
already turned off. And at that point
when I was in internal affairs, when
they asked me to do this or that, like I
gave them the bare minimum. And you
know, I I kept to myself and um they
they started to retaliate against me,
changed my schedule around,
um working all different type of hours,
exhausting me physically, then mentally,
screaming on me, uh nitpicking on me for
every little thing, my bad evaluations
and all this other stuff. And my union
rep, um he worked in group seven at the
time.
And he was the only union rep that
actually helped me in the union.
>> Wow. Right? And he
helped me because
one, he was about to retire. He was on
his way out.
Um two, he worked in group seven, which
was the the TARU um the tech people.
They gave you the fake IDs. Um they
listened to all the recordings. They
retrieved all the recordings and stuff
like that. And he saw the recording
before they edited before they lost it.
Right? Or before, you know, they decide
to discard it.
And he's like, "Steve, I know you did a
great job out there.
I don't know why they're coming after
you.
But it seems like they got them watching
orders and you should get yourself a
lawyer."
So, I said, "Great. All right.
Let's call the union. Let me get a union
lawyer."
He goes, "No.
Don't use the union. The union's going
to use it as a bargaining chip. You
should go out and get a private lawyer."
So, I went out. I searched for a private
lawyer. I got a private lawyer, which
cost me money, right? Even though, you
know, some people do a contingency, but
you still got to put
a retainer down.
Um then all of a sudden I was
transferred out.
And I got administrative desk duty um at
the police academy.
And you know, just
off the streets. One, I was kind of um
relieved cuz they wanted to put me back
in the street. They wanted they wanted
to put me back in the in this
in precincts where these cops that I
investigated that got away
were working.
Mhm. And I'm like,
"That's the whole point of you bringing
me to internal affairs. This is my
safety. I can't go back out."
>> getting shot. Right? It's like just like
Serpico. So, that popped into my head
right away. Like, I'm going to get shot
like Serpico. Right? And when my lawyer
pushed for it, like, you know, that's
when I got
um transferred to uh
the police academy and stuff. And at
least I was off the street. Right?
Um
I decided to run for politics cuz at
that time I was like, you know what?
They're not going to do anything. I need
to get into position of power to one,
protect myself,
>> It's good thinking.
>> and to push for change. So, I I figured,
look, there's corruption every
government in every um
part of the government, right? So, city,
state, federal. Right? So, I'm thinking
city has its own corruption. State has a
their own corruption. And so does
federal. But
how it works is
state will be willing to enforce
corruption on the city
in order to keep up this illusion of
them actually doing their job,
yet still have their own state
corruption going on.
So, it's possible for me to get into a
state position where I could create a
community-based agency to oversee the
NYPD instead of NYPD overseeing itself.
So, I ran for state assembly.
Right?
Um
politics is even worse
>> [gasps]
>> than law enforcement. Um
it was so bad. It it it
I was doxxed. I was gaslit.
Um
The DSA are just so vicious.
So vicious and
gaslighting, like just making up stuff
and
destroying your mental health. Right?
Um
after I lost the election,
it kind of gave the green light to NYPD
to come down on me even harder
because um the incumbent that I ran
against
wrote a letter basically saying
"Hey, investigate this guy." Whatever.
So, now the NYPD is like, "Oh, we got
green lights from the politicians as
well."
>> Oh my god.
So, they came down on me hard. Um
I was sitting in my patrol car.
My lieutenant came to, you know, and
just started
screaming on me
for no reason.
For some reason, that that was like kind
of like the straw that broke my back and
I remember taking out my service um
pistol.
I had a Glock.
Um
I put it to my my chin and
I was ready I was ready to end it.
Um
I was scared mostly because of my
family.
They They retaliate They don't just go
after you, they go after your family,
too, right? So,
their their playbook, for some reason, I
seen it happen to you, too, right? So,
their playbook is
exhaust you physically, exhaust you
mentally,
destroy you financially,
dirty you dirty your rep up,
and then hopefully you go kill yourself
or you get killed.
Right?
And um
my thing was they already sent my
daughter to the psych ward once out of
out of uh you know,
junior high school. She was in uh lab
and whatever, they sent her to the psych
ward.
My My wife was pregnant with my new with
my son
at the time.
My political opponent doxxed us in the
middle of the Black Lives Matter
movement and said, "Here's a racist and
corrupt cop, and here's his address."
Oh my god.
And I was like, "You know what? I don't
want my family go do this.
And if I took myself out the picture,
then maybe they'll stop, right?"
So,
everything was going bad for me and I
was like, "You know what? I'll probably
[__] this up, too, killing myself. I'll
probably just end up like being a
vegetable or something like that." Yeah.
>> So, I took out, you know, I unloaded I
did some dry runs. I'm like, "All right,
should I do it this angle, this angle,
whatever?"
And at that around that time, a lot of
cops were committing suicide. And um
thank god they they created this app
where you could go on and get outside
counseling instead of NYPD in in-house
counseling, right?
And I was like, "You know what?
I don't want them to win.
[__] them. I'm not going to let them
win.
So, I reached out
to a counselor
at um Columbia University and uh
I got on meds.
Uh the job found out, took away my gun,
Ugh. put me on even worse desk duty.
Um
and you know, I slowly recovered from
that.
But legally wise and harassment didn't
stop.
So, I kept on getting harassed at work.
Um
this goes on for like maybe
until 2022, right? So, after COVID,
I haven't gone out in a while.
My friend's birthday, he asked me go out
to the club and just like, you know,
celebrate, go out, have a drink. He's
like, "Look, I know you've been through
a lot. Just come out, have a drink with
the guys and you know, try to forget
about things." I go out. I see my female
friend
there and long story short, she gets
sexually assaulted. I break them up. I
tell the security guard. Security guard
breaks them up.
The guy refuses to leave.
He then turns around minutes later,
sexually assaults her again. It's all on
camera, right?
I then tell her, "Go over there." Let me
tell the security guard again. Tell the
security guard again. He refuses to
leave again. I turn around to call the
boyfriend over to let the boyfriend
know, "Hey, this is your problem. It's
not my problem. It's not my girl, you
know, I'm
Yeah, the person, right? Trying to
protect somebody.
But the boyfriend, as I'm calling the
boyfriend over, I turn back around, I
see her and the guy interlocked. They're
like pulling each other's shirt. I push
the guy back.
You know, I hit him twice in the head.
There was no injuries. It was broken up
right away, just within seconds.
Everybody gets kicked out of the club.
Boyfriend finds out, knocks the guy out.
I tell him, "Look, the guy's knocked
out. I think he's good. Stop." He stops.
We turn around. His friends are trying
to come at us. The security guard's
holding them back and whatever.
Next day, they put on social media,
"Unprovoked attack."
I'm like, "This is bullshit."
Um
when the cops that investigated saw this
online. You're good.
>> Asian community is very small, right?
Um
He He confers with the cop I did arrest.
First of all, that's criminal
association,
right?
Confers with the cops I did arrest.
Reports it to the same Internal Affairs
Group that I was undercover with
and that I was suing and whistleblowing
on.
They go out and investigate. They arrest
me for acting in concert.
They said, "You were standing there. You
didn't stop the attack." I go, "Yeah,
because there's like five bouncers
standing there, also.
And I'm off duty. I'm not going to jump
into the fight where five bouncers are
scrambling around and they don't know
who's who and they get I'm going to end
up getting punched by a security guard.
So, yeah, of course I'm just standing
there making sure I'm not being attacked
or, you know, anybody else is being
attacked, you know? Like people behind
me, I'm
making sure everybody is separated,
right?"
>> [snorts]
>> Charged me acting in concert.
Nobody else was arrested, though. So,
how do I act in concert with somebody
else when nobody else is arrested?
The person who ends up knocking the kid
out, he turns himself in a year later,
right? Confesses to everything. Pleads
guilty to felony charges. And yet they
tell him, "Yeah, we're not interested in
you."
He doesn't get any jail time. Felony
charges. Get no jail time.
Stayed out of jail for 3 years. Gets
repled down to a misdemeanor.
End of that.
Me? They fire me before my trial starts,
right?
Two Two years after that my my trial
starts. In 2024, my trial starts.
I beat the felony charges.
So, I I get found guilty of um hitting
the guy inside. They said that was
attempted assault, right? Which is
basically harassment, right? For it not
to be assault, you have to have
injuries. And you can ask any cop if
they ever took a report for attempted
assault. There's no such charge. It's
either assault or harassment, right?
Because if you push somebody and there's
no injuries,
it's harassment.
And the cop has to be there to witness
it to be able to issue a summons, right?
If you punch somebody and they say,
"Ouch, it hurt."
That's an assault,
right? Because it's physical injury.
The kid said he didn't it didn't hurt
inside whatever. Okay, fine. Attempted
assault.
Then another assault charge on this kid
that got beat up by other people
and the camera view is from me
across street
where cars are passing by and you can't
even see anything. They go, "Oh, yeah,
you hit the kid somewhere over there cuz
he said so."
I go, "What are you talking about? I'm
screaming at the kid cuz the that kid
just beat up another girl at the scene."
All right, whatever the case case is,
fine.
Um probation office interviews me cuz
after you you know, you after the trial,
you have to go interview with a
probation office, right? And the
probation office asked me, "Hey, do you
plan on appealing?"
And I go, "Well, I had a public defender
because the lawyer I hired right end up
being in bed with the DAs, right? So,
what you what I learned is the DA's
office and the police department, they
work hand in hand.
Forget this whole illusion of DA hates
the police, the police hates the DA. No.
Everybody works hand in hand. It's all
part of the same body. It's just the
right
>> of judges were um
assistant district attorneys earlier in
their careers. Yeah.
>> So, it's like the right arm, the left
arm, and the head, and the body. It's
all the same body, right? So, they all
work together. Judges, the DAs, the
police department, the corrections
department. They all work together.
Okay?
So,
when I interview with the probation
office, you know, I had a public
defender at that at the end of my trial
I end up having a public public
defender, right? That was the only
person I I I could go with and that only
person I could afford after all these
lawsuits and stuff like that over the
course of 8 years, right?
So,
>> [clears throat]
>> um I tell him, "Look, I think my public
defender automatically appeals."
They okay, um do you want to talk about
the case or did he direct you not to
talk about it? I said, "I He directed me
not to talk about it." They okay.
>> [snorts]
>> At the sentencing,
which is like a month later after, you
know, the jury
um
announced their their conviction, right?
At the sentencing,
the judge goes,
"Steve Steven Lee, this has nothing to
do with the Chinese Exclusion Act. This
has nothing to do with Chinese racism or
you being Asian. This has nothing to do
with NYPD retaliating against you or the
system retaliating against you. This has
nothing to do with, you know, um
corruption or anything like that.
You claim
that you plan on appealing
and that shows me that you show no
remorse for what you did.
And therefore, I'm sentencing you for 6
months for the assault three
and 3 months for the attempted assault
three
to run concurrent.
Bailiff, take him away.
And
I didn't get time to turn myself in cuz
usually they give you time to turn
yourself in and stuff like that, get
your stuff in order. I was going there
thinking I was getting probation cuz
probation officers recommended probation
and anger management classes. The DA
wanted a year, which was ridiculous,
right? So, the judge gave me 9 months.
And I'm like, what is going on? Like,
wait a second.
First of all, who said anything about
the China Exclusion Act? Where the hell
did that come from?
Who said anything about, you know, like
>> That That in and of itself should be
basis for appeal.
Right. So, then I was like, what Who
mentioned anything about police
retaliation? Yeah.
I mentioned it,
but not during the trial.
It didn't come up during trial.
So, how you even know about it?
Right?
How you know about that? All these
people that that arrested me and all
these people that testify against me I
actually has civil lawsuits against and,
you know, I was blowing the whistle on.
Like, how did you know about that?
Down to the point where the person that
was delivering at the DA's office, one
of the cops transferred from internal
affairs, went into the DA's office,
worked for the DA, and he was the one
that handed the video to them. Like,
all these people I used to work with in
internal affairs that I was suing.
And that I was saying were corrupt.
So, what are the cases?
They take me to the back. The court
officer is like shaking his head. I'm
like, what the [__] just happened?
Because this is Manhattan, New York.
Nobody gets jail time for assault.
>> you can push somebody in front of a
subway train and not get jail time.
Right. Exactly. You know what I mean?
Like, what is going on? Like, my my case
should have been thrown out.
Right? So, the court officer is shaking
his head. He's like, we don't know what
just happened. Like, that usually
doesn't happen. We're disappointed, too.
We have no idea.
My lawyer comes in to the back. I I ask
him the same thing. What just happened?
He goes, "Ugh, he's a tough judge. What
do you want me to tell you?"
And I go, "Are you [__] kidding me?"
So,
I go straight to Rikers.
All right. Um And that had to be
terrifying because you're a police
officer and you're going to be thrown in
with these animals that are at Rikers.
And Rikers is known as probably the most
violent jail in America. Yeah.
And you mean institution?
>> Inhumane. The The legislature has
ordered it closed like six different
times. The city just ignores them.
>> It's It's under federal jurisdiction
now. That's right. Um
So,
the sitting in back of the van
going to Rikers
was
I don't know. I I just it felt so real.
Like, I I wasn't I was like, this can't
be [__] happening. I mean, this can't
be real. Somebody's going to hop out and
be like, "Okay, we're just kidding."
Right? Like, what's what's going on?
Like, I can't
I can't believe this is Am Am I
Am I sleeping? Am I imagining? Am I
hallucinating? Is this Is this
Are my meds [__] me up? Like, where
What is going on?
So, it takes about like an hour to get
there, right? Because they had to drop
people off at other prisoners at
Bellevue and stuff like that. And
um
when I get to Rikers,
the correction officer there was like,
"Don't worry. We know who you are. We'll
take care of you."
I thought it was a
I thought it was a good sign Yeah.
>> Yeah. I'm like, all right.
Maybe, you know, they'll show some
courtesy and they know what happened. I
got [__] over and these are some good
people that, you know, look out for me.
So,
they take my stuff away,
you know, strip me naked, squat, cough.
I put on my um they had um browns there.
Right? The uniform is brown.
I put on the browns, put on these kung
fu shoes looking things.
Take me to my cell.
Uh I was protected custody.
They shackle me. So, they order me to be
in a box it's called, right? Where
>> I got the box.
>> are shackled.
>> Oh, yeah.
And those are shackled to your waist.
Mhm.
>> Your waist is then shackled to your leg
shackles. Mhm. And I'm walking like
this. And they put a steel box over the
the wrist shackles so that you can't
pick the pick the cuffs and escape.
Ridiculous.
>> they claim it's for your own safety.
Yeah. Right. Sure.
>> "How is this for my safety? If somebody
comes attacking at attacking me, cuz
nobody else is cuffed.
Right? The hallways are supposed to be
clean before you walk, right? Nobody
else is supposed to be around. But, it's
just it's unfeasible.
They don't have enough manpower to do
that. So, they let other prisoners just
walking around and stuff. So, I'm like,
how's this for my own safety? They come
charging at me. How am I going to defend
myself? I'm supposed to defend I'm
supposed to depend on you, the guy who's
handicapping me?
You know? So, what are the cases? I'm
walking to my cell. They put me in
protected custody. I'm in my own room in
solitary.
On the same block that I learned later
on
all murderers.
All murderers. One guy who chopped the
head off the the godfather of the bloods
and stuff like that in the in the Bronx.
Another guy who was a drug dealer gone
bad, murdered the guy. And then later on
they transferred over officers, dealers,
cop killers um
on the same block.
And all of them were very aggressive
towards me. So, we all share the same
phone line. So, when you want the phone,
you have to
tell them to get off the phone
in order for you to use the phone. Or
you have to wait forever, which never
comes around, right?
>> [clears throat]
>> I make phone call out.
And then um
you know,
I'm talking to my people make sure that
my car was given back to my wife and
stuff like that, my keys and everything
got back.
Um one of the COs, before I made the
phone call though, one of the COs
uh the sergeants there are ranked
captains, right?
So, they don't have the sergeant rank.
They go straight to captain.
And she's walking with me. She's talking
to me. She's like, "What happened?"
And I go, "It was a bar fight.
My female friend got sexually assaulted.
I told the bouncer. I They The fight got
broken up.
Boyfriend end up knocking a kid out.
Boyfriend gets no jail time. I get jail
time."
And they're like, "Yeah, you you were
beating kids, right?" And I was like,
"What What the [__] you talking about?
They're all adults. They're in the bar.
They're over like They're all [__] in
their 20s and stuff and 30s maybe,
right?"
>> [snorts]
>> And they're like, "Oh, okay. I'm glad I
got the story from you directly. I'm
glad I talked to you directly." So, then
after that I got a better room, you
know, stuff like that. But, before I was
I was like it felt like a scene out of a
horror movie where the lights are
flickering, the bed is
inclined, the TV is stuck on one channel
blasting and I can't change the channel.
I can't lower the volume. I couldn't
sleep. It was freezing in the room. I
had no blanket, no pillow. Couldn't
sleep down.
Next day, once they found out that that
wasn't I wasn't a child beater, you
know, I was thinking like, where the
[__] they get this from, right?
So, when I called my friend up, he said,
"We checked your record and that the
court clerk had add a false charge,
right? Said caregiver abuser, which
meant child abuser."
So, people were in there thinking,
"Here's a corrupt cop that's beating
kids."
They did that on purpose to cause you
harm.
Yes. They were hoping somebody would
take it out on you. Right. But, that's
what That's what they hate the most
inside is sexual offenders and child
abusers.
>> child, yeah. Exactly. And And that that
marks you for death automatically.
Right? It's a death sentence.
When we went out to the yard,
we were all individually escorted out.
And then we were put in another cage
fence,
right? But, the cage fences are, you
know, it's right next to each other.
So, I'm talking to them next to me
to the guy next to me cuz I had to get
out of the room. It was just You can't
be in the room all day. No, you go
crazy.
Yeah, it was good for like the first
couple of days to like try to like
meditate and get some silence and like
trying to regather my thoughts and
everything and you know, settle in and
um
observe the situation. But, then after a
while I had to get out. So, I went out
to the yard.
You know, they're all doing their I
straight out of the movies where they're
doing their um
their their their
burpees and stuff like that, right?
Going down, go jump up, whatever.
Everybody do the same time to work out
together.
The guy next to me wasn't working out.
So, you know, I introduced myself. I I
knew they knew I was a cop right. So, I
told him straight up what happened and
my story before that. He's like,
"Oh, wow.
I'm glad you talked to me cuz, you know,
we were about to like make a move on
you."
>> Yeah, they give you a beat down.
>> see that they were setting you up.
They're trying to get you, you know,
murdered in here. So, don't worry. We
know how corrupt they are cuz, you know,
everybody in there
knows how corrupt NYPD is, right?
And they're like, "Don't worry. We got
your back."
So,
from that moment on like I I trusted the
inmates more than I trusted the COs,
the correction officers.
And some of the correction officers I
actually worked with before.
And I was actually friends with. And
when I went in there they were just
like, "Fuck this guy. This guy's a rat.
[__] him, right?" And
I saw that interview that you had with
uh that other ex-CIA agent
Andrew, whatever his name is. The Oh,
Bustamante.
Every Every Yeah. Everyday Spy Guy.
Yeah. And um
>> when when he was like, "Why did you do
that? Why would you do that? Why would
you do that?" And it's like, and you you
said that one thing, "Oh, you're a true
believer."
And
I faced that so many times
explaining to other police officers
sometimes where they're like, "Why would
you do that? Why would you do that? You
know, you sold out your own people." And
I'm like, "Are you [__] kidding me?"
Are you [__] kidding me? Are you Are
you Are you like that naive?
You know what I mean? Like, you think
they're going to protect you?
No.
Today it's me, tomorrow it's you. That's
right.
As soon as you cross that line
you're under the bus.
Don't think for one moment they're going
to be like, "Oh, this guy, he he helped
us fight crime and stuff and all these
other things and keep people safe." No,
they don't give a [__] about that.
Their their thing is
who's going to protect this system of
ours?
Mhm. Right? That's right.
>> Who's going to keep the wheels turning?
That's the only people they they
promote. That's the only people they
protect
are people who keep the wheels turning.
They don't give a [__] about fighting
corruption. They don't care about
justice. They don't care about
integrity.
No. They care about money coming in.
Money coming to our pockets and the
wheels keep turning.
That's all they care about.
And you know, after after all that, like
I guess they left me alone for a little
bit now. Um you know, I lost my 18-year
pension.
I had a uh line of duty injury
that they actually approved for me to
get disability from NYPD, which is uh we
call it three quarters, right? It's the
accidental disability that I'm supposed
to get from the department. And they
said, "Nope. Sorry, you got fired before
it came across our our desk." And I was
like, "Yeah, but I put in the
application before that."
It's just you guys stalled it to the
point where I got fired and then it came
across your desk. And now you tell me
you can't handle it because it's I'm
fired now because it came across your
desk when it was fired. Like it was it's
just craziness. So
I'm pensionless, you know, um
I'm financially broken. I'm trying to
recover back. My wife had to work now.
Um
You know, you and I are in the same
We're in the same boat here. I lost my
pension.
Um my friends walked away from me. Lost
my freedom. In the end, I lost my
family.
Uh there's almost no upside. I mean, I
And I know you'll agree with me on this.
There's almost no upside. The upside is
you know you did the right thing. You
know in your heart that you're the good
guy.
They're the bad guys. It's the system
that's corrupt. But there's no there's
no getting around the fact that
it could take decades to rebuild what
you lost.
Yeah. Yeah. So
losing my family wise like
I
almost even to this day, even even now,
like
it's on rocky ground. Sure.
Sure.
>> Uh the financial burden it it hinders a
lot.
Um my wife, she's she's from China. So
she's not Americanized and stuff like
that. So thank god. Like I think it a
uh
if I had an American wife, like she
would have left me a long time ago,
right?
But um
you know
in in our culture it's like we don't
really believe in divorce like that,
right? We we try to stick it through
thick thick and thin, you know, and we
you know, we help each other. I I speak
to a lot of whistleblowers. Even like
when uh when the NYPD cops the
that was arrested for being a Chinese
spy. Right.
>> And then Yes.
>> he was he was put in federal prison for
6 months in solitary where they tried to
make him take a deal. And then he end up
saying no. And then they end up dropping
the charges and since then they didn't
go.
And you know, I speak to him and him and
his wife like, you know, also like going
through it. It's it's hard. It's very
hard. Um
yeah. Broken financially and stuff like
that. The only thing The only upside is
yes, I did the right thing. Yeah, that's
it. Right.
>> You did the right thing.
>> Um
but
now the question is
do you believe in God? Do you believe in
a higher force? And if so, like I I I
believe in in a higher force. Uh you
know, the whole
is is he called God or whatever? I don't
know what he's called, but I do believe
there is a higher force, a higher
energy, like karma, um you know, the
laws of the universe that you just can't
deny, right?
And I ask myself
why?
Why you allow this happen to me
if I did the right thing?
You know, like
where's their karma? Yeah. What's going
on? It'll come. It'll take time. It'll
take time. But you know, I blew the
whistle Yeah I blew the whistle in 2007.
I got arrested in 2012. I went to prison
in 2013. Got out in 2015.
My life was in shambles. But here we are
11 years later
and the bad guys now are facing grand
juries and facing felony charges. And
now it's going to be their turn. So
there really is such a thing as karma.
Before we go on to our next question, I
want to give you a word from one of our
sponsors. I want to talk about something
that really matters to me. That's
medical freedom and being able to make
your own health care decisions. That's
why I'm proud to partner with All Family
Pharmacy.
All Family Pharmacy is a US-based
licensed compounding pharmacy that works
with licensed providers to give people
access to medications like Ivermectin,
for example, or Mebendazole. And they
ship directly to your door. I like All
Family Pharmacy because they believe,
like I do, that patients should have
options. They should have privacy and
the right to be proactive about their
health. You don't wait until your house
is on fire to buy a fire extinguisher,
for example. Well, it's the same idea
here. So take control and get prepared
today. Go to allfamilypharmacy.com/john
and use my code john10
to get 10% off your order. That's
allfamilypharmacy.com/john
promo code j o h n 10. When I was in
prison and I started seeing
you know, all those news come out and
all that stuff and they started getting
indicted after I started, you know, um
I guess you call it praying, right?
>> Yeah. You know.
A lot of stuff started coming out. And I
just sit back and I laugh.
And I go, "Haha."
You know,
I told you the truth will come out.
Yep.
>> And it does. And
>> It does.
>> [clears throat]
>> But thing is, you know
I used to want to shed more light to it.
I'm hoping that, you know, people will
will hear what's going on and actually
good people that are, you know, in the
department still and actually good
people that are in government or
whatever
that they will care enough and be brave
enough to actually want to do something
and, you know, ask you know uh
people like us to help them reform it
and change it so it doesn't happen to
anybody else. That's it. That's why we
have to keep up the fight. As hard as
things are, that's exactly why we have
to keep up the fight.
>> Absolutely. Absolutely. And you know,
like so now that's why I started my own
podcast and, you know, I also um I work
I do like community stuff, food pantries
and helping people and just
you know, just continue helping people
out there and one day I'll I'll run for
office again and then, you know,
hopefully I get in a position of power
where I could introduce a bill
to actually make sure that this doesn't
happen to anybody else, right? So like I
said, I work with Serpico. Serpico
Serpico put me in contact with the
Government Accountability Project, Tom
Devine and everybody. They represented
me as well.
Yeah, so Tom Devine was actually going
to put in So get get this timing, right?
So now people are like, "It sounds too
perfect where you might have been set
up, right?" And
you know
I was working with Tom Devine and we
were about to put in a federal lawsuit
against the NYPD.
I foiled the NYPD for my stuff.
And 2 weeks later I that incident
happened and I get arrested.
Yeah, that sounds like a setup. Right?
>> Yeah, that's a setup.
>> find out also that the Commissioner
Caban, right? Under his administration
under the Adams administration is when I
got fired extra fast. Right? Then you
find out Caban is actually
facing federal charges for the same kind
of corruption that I arrested these
people for and that I was trying to
expose. And the nightclub that a hap-
the incident happened
was one of the nightclubs that Caban was
extorting.
Unbelievable.
>> by
Steven, um tell us about your podcast.
Where can people hear it? Where can they
uh they get involved and listen to it?
>> It's right here on YouTube. Um it's
System Unfiltered.
Uh you could just or you could look at
my website stevefornewyork.com
s t e v f o r n e w y o r k.com. And it
has all my social links there, you know.
Excellent.
>> yeah, you got to keep the fight going.
Hopefully, you know, there's some good
people that will see it. And you know,
hopefully uh
I know a lot of people are saying things
about Mandamian stuff, but I think it's
too early to judge. Um
I would hope that he would, you know,
want to make some real changes and
stuff.
>> Yeah, I sure hope so.
>> Think corruption. Well, thanks for
joining us, man, and very, very best of
luck. I know exactly what you're going
through.
Yeah. Forge those alliances with the
likes of Tom Devine and people at the
Government Accountability Project. There
are people who are on your side and, you
know, together we really can make
changes.
Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Thanks for being with us. That's
why I wanted to come on the show cuz I
know that, you you know, you you've been
through the same thing.
Yeah.
Yeah, it's not easy.
It's worth it in the end.
What was funny is they use the same
playbook. Yeah, they do. Against all of
us.
And they didn't just invent it. I mean,
look at Serpico.
Yeah. It's the same situation.
>> It just doesn't change. For some reason,
it's just
I I don't know what it is. And it's just
nobody
When you when you cry out for help, it
seems like it falls on deaf ears. All
these people that are calling for
accountability and stuff like that, they
are the ones that ignore you the most.
Yeah, you know, and it's the truth.
>> it's just crazy. It's just
It's the truth. Well, thanks for being
with us. It's
It's good to see you. Good to meet you.
>> Thank you, John. Good to meet you, too.
>> All the best.
>> Hopefully we can talk. I look forward to
it.